A few days later,
June 22, you could confirm that one found
wreckage from titanium near Titanic
And most likely all five people had on board.
Died.
The cause is believed to be an implosion.
What was Oceangate for companies?
How was the submarine Titan constructed and what risks were there?
What really happened and what is an implosion?
was made of carbon fiber and titanium.
It was equipped with four electric engines,
Two vertical and two horizontal.
These could steer the boat forward, backward,
up and down and rotate it.
The maximum speed was 3 knots,
which is about 5.5 km/h.
Oxygen to the entire crew would last for 96 hours if something
Would go wrong and it was built to cope with a depth of 4000 meters.
The pilot steered the entire submarine with a modified wireless game control.
Which meant that you did not have to have any special security rules.
Titanium was not approved as seaworthy by any authority or organization
And all passengers on board must also sign an agreement
where you confirm that you are aware of all risks, that it is all an experiment
and that it can result in physical harm,
trauma or death.
The agreement briefly gives the Oceangate back free
If something would go wrong.
One of the founders, Stockton Rush told in an interview from 2021 to quote
In 2018, David Lochridge wrote the then head of Oceangates
marine operations, a report in which he expressed his concern about titanium
He wanted the submarine to be inspected and be certified
by an authority, but Oceangate did not want it.
They refused to pay for such an inspection.
Another thing he expressed in his report was that the window that was on titanium.
was just certified and approved for a depth of 1300 meters,
About a third of the depth required to get down to Titanic.
Oceangate did not like Lochridge's statements so they sued him and kicked him.
Then we have to
Also talk about the choice of material for titanium,
Carbon fiber and titanium.
Carbon fiber is an extremely strong and lightweight material that is known for its high
tensile strength.
Thus, the ability to withstand forces that pull the material apart.
However, it is not as strong when it comes to pressure strength
which is the ability to withstand the power that compresses the material.
At extremely high pressure that one encounters down in the sea
Can carbon fiber based structures crack.
Titanic, on the other hand, is known for its high compressive strength,
Which makes it a good choice for vehicles that will dive far below the water.
But it is much heavier and more expensive than carbon fiber.
To combine titanium
and carbon fiber may seem like a good idea to take advantage
of both carbon fiber's ease and titanium compressive strength.
But at these extreme pressure down in the sea, the parts can
immediately and hence we need something that can protect us from the pressure,
For example, a submarine.
But then it is important that the submarine is designed to cope with the pressure.
At 3800 meters depth the pressure is so great that the submarine is pressed together
From all directions and edges with a force corresponding to about 10 \ H000 tonnes.
It's like having the weight of the Eiffel Tower pressing against the submarine,
But not just from above but from all directions.
Back to June 18, 2023.
When the time is on its way down to Titanic
This is thus the pressure from the outside that compresses the thought, which has a vacuum inside.
And this is just the pressure from our atmosphere on the surface.
Thus, the pressure from only one atmosphere.
Implosion that happened for the crew inside the titanium
was exposed to 380 atmospheres.
So you can only imagine how fast it went.
They never even got to react to something happening,
Which might be just as good.
It was a brief summary
by the company Oceangate.
The accident with titanium ..